const prepositionsButton=document.querySelector(".prepositions"),tenseButton=document.querySelector(".tense"),idiomsButton=document.querySelector(".idioms"),pageContainer=document.querySelector(".page__wrapper"),headerContainer=document.querySelector(".header__wrapper"),categoriesToHide=document.querySelectorAll(".first"),answersToShow=document.querySelectorAll(".second"),questionButton=document.querySelectorAll(".page__btn"),questionField=document.querySelector(".header__question"),answersContainer=document.querySelector(".page__answers"),nextButton=document.querySelector(".next"),finishButton=document.querySelector(".finish"),questioncounter=document.querySelector(".header__counter"),correctAnswersArea=document.querySelector(".correct__answer"),incorrectAnswersArea=document.querySelector(".incorrect__answer");let shuffledQuestions,currentQuestionIndex,correctAnswers=0,incorrectAnswers=0;const prepositionsQuestions=[{question:"My dad usually wakes up ___ 6 a.m.",answers:[{text:"at",correct:!0},{text:"in",correct:!1},{text:"on",correct:!1},{text:"from",correct:!1}]},{question:"I have a birthday ____ May.",answers:[{text:"at",correct:!1},{text:"in",correct:!0},{text:"on",correct:!1},{text:"from",correct:!1}]},{question:"Every week ___ Monday my friend goes to school ___ 8 a.m.",answers:[{text:"at/on",correct:!1},{text:"in/in",correct:!1},{text:"on/at",correct:!0},{text:"in/at",correct:!1}]},{question:"You have to finish the assignment ____ Friday",answers:[{text:"till",correct:!1},{text:"by",correct:!0},{text:"on",correct:!1},{text:"at",correct:!1}]},{question:"Students have to stay at school ___ 4 p.m. every day",answers:[{text:"till",correct:!0},{text:"on",correct:!1},{text:"by",correct:!1},{text:"from",correct:!1}]},{question:"I usually brush my teeth ___ the morning",answers:[{text:"on",correct:!1},{text:"at",correct:!1},{text:"till",correct:!1},{text:"in",correct:!0}]},{question:"John started doing his homework ___ 8 p.m. and finished only ___ midnight",answers:[{text:"on/at",correct:!1},{text:"at/at",correct:!0},{text:"in/in",correct:!1},{text:"at/in",correct:!1}]},{question:"It often snows __ winter",answers:[{text:"at",correct:!1},{text:"on",correct:!1},{text:"in",correct:!0},{text:"from",correct:!1}]},{question:"Kate got married ___ the age of 19",answers:[{text:"from",correct:!1},{text:"at",correct:!1},{text:"in",correct:!0},{text:"on",correct:!1}]},{question:"My friend was born ___ 1985",answers:[{text:"in",correct:!0},{text:"at",correct:!1},{text:"___",correct:!1},{text:"on",correct:!1}]}],tenseQuestions=[{question:"When I ____ in the park yesterday, I ___ a little kitten under the bench",answers:[{text:"was walking / saw",correct:!0},{text:"was walking / see",correct:!1},{text:"walked / saw",correct:!1},{text:"walk/ see",correct:!1}]},{question:"I ___ at 7 a.m. yesterday",answers:[{text:"wake up",correct:!1},{text:"woke up",correct:!0},{text:"was waking up",correct:!1},{text:"am waking up",correct:!1}]},{question:"Dan ___ a new car las month",answers:[{text:"buys",correct:!1},{text:"is buying",correct:!1},{text:"bought",correct:!0},{text:"buy",correct:!1}]},{question:"It usually ___ a lot in March",answers:[{text:"rain",correct:!1},{text:"is raining",correct:!1},{text:"raining",correct:!1},{text:"rains",correct:!0}]},{question:"Paul ____ at the moment",answers:[{text:"is not working",correct:!0},{text:"does not work",correct:!1},{text:"is not work",correct:!1},{text:"is not worked",correct:!1}]},{question:"Look at these clouds, it ________",answers:[{text:"rains",correct:!1},{text:"is raining",correct:!1},{text:"is going to rain",correct:!0},{text:"rained",correct:!1}]},{question:"This is the best book I ______",answers:[{text:"ever read",correct:!1},{text:"ever reading",correct:!1},{text:"have ever readed",correct:!1},{text:"have ever read",correct:!0}]},{question:'Shakespear____ "Romeo and Juliet", _____ he',answers:[{text:"write / didn't",correct:!1},{text:"wrote / didn't",correct:!0},{text:"wrote / did",correct:!1},{text:"write / did",correct:!1}]},{question:"The train ____ at 5 p.m. tomorrow",answers:[{text:"arrive",correct:!1},{text:"arrived",correct:!1},{text:"arriving",correct:!1},{text:"arrives",correct:!0}]},{question:"We ___ all our money already!",answers:[{text:"have spent",correct:!0},{text:"have spend",correct:!1},{text:"spend",correct:!1},{text:"spent",correct:!1}]}],idiomsQuestions=[{question:"Peter is a real pain in the neck",answers:[{text:"Peter is annoying everyone",correct:!0},{text:"Peter has a pain i his neck",correct:!1},{text:"Peter likes to hit other people",correct:!1},{text:"Peter is too sleepy",correct:!1}]},{question:"Jim kicked the bucket last year",answers:[{text:"Jim found the big bucket last year",correct:!1},{text:"Jim had the fight last year",correct:!1},{text:"Jim passed away last year",correct:!0},{text:"Jim started the new life last year",correct:!1}]},{question:"I am gonna put it in a nutshell",answers:[{text:"I am gonna hide it",correct:!1},{text:"I am gonna stop doing it",correct:!1},{text:"I am gonna eat some nuts",correct:!1},{text:"I am gonna explain some complicated idea",correct:!0}]},{question:"Let's start the ball rolling!",answers:[{text:"I want you to play basketball",correct:!1},{text:"I want you to pick the ball up",correct:!1},{text:"I want you to start doing it",correct:!0},{text:"I want you to give me the ball",correct:!1}]},{question:"She speaks Queen's English",answers:[{text:"She speaks standard pure English",correct:!0},{text:"She speaks like a queen",correct:!1},{text:"She does not swear",correct:!1},{text:"She speaks only English",correct:!1}]},{question:"My husband always talks shop",answers:[{text:"My husband always wants to go shopping",correct:!1},{text:"My husband always talks about shops",correct:!1},{text:"My husband hates shopping",correct:!1},{text:"My husband always talks about work",correct:!0}]},{question:"The teacher finally got the word out",answers:[{text:"The teacher finally started speaking",correct:!1},{text:"The teacher finally found the word he wanted to say",correct:!0},{text:"The teacher finally made his students speak",correct:!1},{text:"The teacher finally made a sound",correct:!1}]},{question:"My friend drinks like a fish",answers:[{text:"My friend drinks a little water",correct:!1},{text:"My friends drinks only water",correct:!1},{text:"My friend drinks too much alcohol",correct:!0},{text:"My friend drinks water and likes fish",correct:!1}]},{question:"My mom has an eye for good food",answers:[{text:"My mom can see food",correct:!1},{text:"My mom can guess what food it is",correct:!1},{text:"My mom always looks for something to eat",correct:!1},{text:"My mom knows what food is good",correct:!0}]},{question:"Death warmed him up",answers:[{text:"He looks really sick",correct:!0},{text:"He is dead",correct:!1},{text:"He killed someone",correct:!1},{text:"He takes a risk to be killed",correct:!1}]}];function startQuiz(e){categoriesToHide.forEach(e=>e.classList.add("hide")),answersToShow.forEach(e=>e.classList.remove("hide")),shuffledQuestions=e.sort(()=>Math.random()-.5),currentQuestionIndex=0,setNextQuestion()}function setNextQuestion(){reset(),showQuestion(shuffledQuestions[currentQuestionIndex])}function showQuestion(e){questionField.innerHTML=e.question,e.answers.forEach(e=>{const t=document.createElement("button");t.innerText=e.text,t.classList.add("page__btn"),e.correct&&(t.dataset.correct=e.correct),t.addEventListener("click",selectAnswer),answersContainer.appendChild(t),questioncounter.innerHTML=`Question ${currentQuestionIndex+1}/${shuffledQuestions.length}`})}function selectAnswer(e){const t=e.target;t.classList.add("active");t.dataset.correct?correctAnswers++:incorrectAnswers++,shuffledQuestions.length>currentQuestionIndex+1&&nextButton.classList.remove("hide"),shuffledQuestions.length==currentQuestionIndex+1&&finishButton.classList.remove("hide")}function reset(){for(nextButton.classList.add("hide");answersContainer.firstChild;)answersContainer.removeChild(answersContainer.firstChild)}function renderFinalPage(){questionButton.forEach(e=>e.classList.add("hide")),finishButton.classList.add("hide"),pageContainer.innerHTML="",pageContainer.innerHTML=`<h3 class="correct__answer">Correct answers: ${correctAnswers}</h3>\n    <h3 class="incorrect__answers">Incorrect answers: ${incorrectAnswers}</h3>\n    <button class="back">Back</button>`;document.querySelector(".back").addEventListener("click",()=>(location.reload(),!1)),headerContainer.innerHTML=`<h2 class="result">Your final result is ${Math.ceil(correctAnswers/shuffledQuestions.length*100)} points</h2>`}prepositionsButton.addEventListener("click",()=>{startQuiz(prepositionsQuestions)}),tenseButton.addEventListener("click",()=>{startQuiz(tenseQuestions)}),idiomsButton.addEventListener("click",()=>{startQuiz(idiomsQuestions)}),nextButton.addEventListener("click",()=>{currentQuestionIndex++,setNextQuestion()}),finishButton.addEventListener("click",renderFinalPage);